Hadi Lashkari Ghouchani

Software Engineer

@ hadi.pro.dev@gmail.com

+34 645 86 91 03

Barcelona, Spain

github.com/hadilq

M medium.com/@hadilq.dev

in linkedin.com/in/hadilq

Summary

A curious developer with over 15 years of experience in software development, where almost 5 years of his experience covers Android development, over 2 years covers teaching algorithms and programming in universities, and over 8 years covers academic and self-employed experiences while he was a student.

An Introvert person who has profound learning and contributing skills. A creative, value driven and passionate developer who enjoys doing math, solving problems and creating scalable, maintainable, testable and efficient apps to make the world a better place to live.

A person whose goal is to surround himself with happy, creative, motivative and clever persons, so his talent becomes flourished.

He's interested in Data Science, Machine Learning, Functional Programming, Differentiable Programming, Category Theory, Math, etc. so constantly looking forward to learning related technologies to use in Mobile apps.

Experience

Senior Android Developer

at Letgo

🛗 Oct. 2019 - Present

Barcelona, Spain

Letgo is the biggest classified marketplace in Turkey with 15+ million apps installed on Android devices

- Fix a couple of bugs and implement multiple features and their A/B Testing
- · Working on variants of Search Alert Entry Points
- Improve the performance of loading feeds by at least a minute
- · Fix multiple Memory leaks
- · Known as "The man who broke the escape room" to emphasize his ability to think out of the box

Technologies:

- · Dagger 2, RxJava 2, Room, etc.
- Agile, Sprint, Github Flow, CI/CD, Dynamic Feature Module Delivery
- Mockito, Espresso, Robolectric, Jacoco, Ktlint, Fastlane
- Atlassian Jira, Atlassian Confluence, Github, Jenkins, Slack, Figma
- New Relic, Firebase, Amplitude, Leanplum, etc.

Lead Android Developer

at Sheypoor

m Jan. 2018 - Jan. 2019

O Tehran, Iran

Sheypoor is one of two lead classified marketplaces in Iran with 1.5+ million users per day, 13+ million overall users and 344+ million sessions.

- Increase the number of users per day from 0.5+ million to 1.5+ million in a year.
- As functional manager of the Android team, he was responsible for the code quality of the Sheypoor app. He coached the team to practice design patterns, clean code, and using app architecture, along with updating libraries and adding new features with focus on agility and UX.
- Implementing new design of the entire app, including rebranding for summer campaign
- · Improving the legacy code quality by adding Dagger and Kotlin.

- Dagger 2, RxJava 2, Butter Knife, Greendao, etc.
- Agile, Kanban, Git Flow, CI/CD
- Mockito, Espresso, Jacoco
- Pivotal Tracker, Github, Jenkins, Slack, Zeplin, etc.

Senior Android Developer

at Myket

m Sep. 2015 - Des. 2017

Tehran, Iran

Myket is one of two lead app stores in Iran with over 8+ million users

Missions:

- Starting TDD and installing Jenking's pipeline to handle CI/CD.
- · Implementing features such as handling deeplinks, search page, inbox page, etc.

Technologies

- Dagger 2, Volley, OneSignal, EventBus, OrmLite, etc.
- · Agile, Scrum, Git Flow
- · Mockito, Espresso
- · Atlassian Jira, Atlassian Confluence, Gitlab, Jfrog, Jenkins

Java and C# developer

at Soha System

mar. 2015 - Aug. 2015

O Tehran, Iran

SOHA is formed to focus on solutions based on smart cards.

Missions

- Implementing RFID card reader Android app via bluetooth connection.
- · Implementing Android and desktop apps

Lecturer

at Universities

m Feb. 2012 - Dec. 2014

Mashhad, Iran

After two years of enrollment by conscription, he had been starting his work in two universities, Payame Noor University and Sadjad University of Technology.

Courses Taught:

· Application of Computers in Physics, Mathematical Physics, etc

Article / Repository

2020 Make Log4k Multiplatform: Simple logging library for Android, iOS, Mac, etc.

2020 Sample App: Provide a full implementation for a No-Framework Dependency Injection in Kotlin 🐧 2020 Contributing on Λrrow Library: Λrrow is a library for Typed Functional Programming in Kotlin

2020 Library: A Kotlin compiler plugin that generates trackable method

1 2020 Medium post: Save State By Using RxJava or Kotlin Flow 2020 Medium post: RxJava instead of LiveData in MVVM

📆 2020 Library: A glue between the lifecycle of LifecycleOwner in Android and upstreams in RxJava

2020 Library: A glue between the lifecycle of LifecycleOwner in Android and Kotlin Coroutines

2020 Library: Simplifier for unnecessary complex lifecycles

2019 Sample App: Functional Programming + Clean Architecture 2019 Sample App: Movie Challenge

2019 Math Library: Modularized, mathematical and multiplatform Kotlin library M 2018 ProAndroidDev post: Logging in Kotlin

🕠 2018 Log4k Library: Easy logging library, but unfortunately it's in Sheypoor repository

M 2018 ProAndroidDev post: Reactive MVVM architectural pattern

2018 Sample App: Clean Architecture + RMVVM ☑ 2018 ProAndroidDev post: Loading entities from database and server API by using RxJava

2018 ProAndroidDev post: LiveData with single events

2018 LiveEvent library: It's useful to propagate single event to View

Education

Sharif University Of Technology Payame Noor University

M.Sc B.Sc in Physics in Physics

m Jul. 2007

Tehran, Iran Mashhad, Iran

Tools / Skills

Android

Lifecycles/LiveData/Navigation/Paging/ViewModel Multidex/Test/Data Binding/WorkManager/Room Android Architecture Components/JetPack Dagger 2/RxJava 2/Retrofit 2/... Kotlin Multiplatform/Kotlin Coroutines Kotlin Compiler Plugin/... View Binding/Butter Knife/ObjectBox/...

Architecture

Clean Architecture/Hexagonal Architecture Unidirectional data flow Architecture MVVM/MVI/MVP/RMVVM

Principle

Clean Code/SOLID Object Oriented Programming Functional Programming Stable Dependencies Principle Stable Abstractions Principle

Design Pattern

Factory/Builder/Singleton/... Adapter/Facade/Proxy/Visitor/.. Strategy/Chain of responsibility/..

Android test library

JUnit/Mockito/Espresso/Jacoco/...

Build Tool

Gradle/Sbt/Maven/Ant/Make/...

Command Line Tool

grep/sed/netstat/awk/docker/.. adb/sdkmanager/avdmanager/...

Development Tool

Pivotal Tracker/Jira/Jenkins/Travis/CircleCi/...

Programing Language

Java/Kotlin/Scala/Haskell/Python Groovy/Dart/Javascript/Rust/..

Linux(Fedora/Ubuntu/Debian), OS X

Operating System

- Special Honor
- 2019 Had an offer from Kik, Kitechener, Canada 2019 Had an offer from Letgo, Barcelona, Spair 2019 Had an offer from CRITICAL Techworks, BMW, Porto,
- Portugal 2019 Had an offer from The Next Big Thing, Berlin, Ger-
- 2018 Received result-oriented badge in Sheypoor
 2007 Ranked 44th among more than five thousand participants in the National Graduate Entrance Exam in

Language

English: Advance Farsi: Native

The source of this resume is in github Built on September 15, 2020